MYLES GRAY

PROFILE

I have considerable experience with enterprise firewalls and switches for high performance networking, configured from the ground up for new networks that include DMZs, VLANs, Stacking, LAG, Redundancy, SSL and IPSec VPNs, Microwave links, Traffic shaping, QOS, AD integration for Single Sign On, RADIUS integration with existing systems and security filtering policies to allow for endpoint control.

I am very competent in Linux CLI and server configuration - including software load balancing (NginX), distributed caching (Memcached), MySQL specialising in high availability.

Particularly proficient configuring and managing VMWare products.

Comfortable configuring FortiOS units, HP ProCurve and Cisco Catalyst switches.

OpenStack implementation for Distributed Private Cloud Computing. Dell PowerConnect 8K series experience with 10Gig networking to include fiber optics, iSCSI MPIO failover and tuning.

Handy with scripting, automation and building bespoke systems.

As a scout leader and web developer I have proven communication and team skills. I enjoy finding problems then working towards their solutions; it leaves me with a sense of achievement, pride and motivates me to try harder things, learn more about the subject and further improve myself.

Strong public speaker, I find it very natural to talk in front of groups including my peers and I interact very well with individuals.

This technical experience coupled with the courses in management I have taken during my studies help me to be more productive and relate to manager's and team member's expectations particularly in the operations field.

EXPERIENCE

NOVOSCO, CLOUDSTREAM ENGINEER - 08/2014 - PRESENT

Infrastructure Engineer in Hosted Platforms/Cloudstream Division

Working with EMC, VMWare, Veeam, Cisco, Fortinet and Microsoft products daily. Very intense, rewarding and challenging.

FREELANCER - 03/2010 - 08/2014

I am a web-developer in my spare time, I love to learn about anything that will enhance performance of web apps and spend great deals of time researching and configuring new virtual setups in ESXi to test new software solutions that could be of benefit.

I have built a number of sites for clients that include: http://www.exitex.com and <a hr

EXITEX LTD, NETWORK & VIRTUALISATION ADMIN - 05/2012 - 08/2014

Responsible for mission critical networking and virtualisation infrastructure redesign to include custom built synchronous replication SANs, 10G, Fiber optic networking, switch stacking, backup/redundancy system design and implementation to allow for automatic HA and clustering failover.

Expansion solutions implemented including microwave links for remote premises, VPNs and a move from a single network to segregation through VLANs company-wide.

Implemented ticketing system to keep track of internal issues, assign to appropriate staff members and supply CTO with reports on common issues and staff performance.

Created documentation wiki for network layouts, iSCSI MPIO failover, software configuration layers (for custom built SANs) and large physical networking and server overhaul/relocation and configuration.

EDUCATION
QUEEN'S UNIVERSITY BELFAST - BSC ,BUSINESS I.T - 2013
Graduated on a 2-1 with Honours, Awarded best final year project in Technology and Business field by PwC.
ABBEY GRAMMAR SCHOOL - 2009
A-Levels - Physics - A, Technology and Design (Systems and Control) - A, Mathematics - B
CERTIFICATIONS
VMWARE
VCP5-DCV (VCP550), VSP-5.5, VSP-SDSD, VSP-DV
CISCO

CCENT R&S, CCNA R&S

HOBBIES & INTERESTS

I have always had an interest in computing hardware/software and performance, this has evolved somewhat into server applications and I love what I do.

Climbing is a huge passion of mine, it leads me to many new places, countries and allows me to meet some amazing people and indulge in my other favourite hobby - photography and videography, examples of both can be found on my site: http://www.mylesgray.com

REFERENCES

Mark Allport - Exitex Ltd, Director - <u>mark.allport@exitex.com</u>

Gerard Lundy - IPOptions, Director - <u>gerard.lundy@ipoptions.com</u>